I will start recording now. So,
Now, this is the course, right? And then when you go
through the module, you should be able to see all the information
about this course. And then you have seen the module one here
already, and then there will be um module 1.2 coming
today. OK, I'll release that today, so you,
you have some time for your next week's study.
And then Um, and then you can see, uh, before you go through this
module, I'll just show you. So this is where we are,
right? So in your home, and that's actually the stuff here,
the, the information here. So this is about general introduction about the
course, and when you go to the learning journey and you will
see. A general
Introduction. And then when you
go to the assessment overview, and you should be able to see how
this course will be assessed. So there will be 40% weekly quiz,
OK, each week worth of 5%. So in total
it's 40%. And then there will be an online exam,
uh, which is proctored, so which means you can't use the
Uh, online, for example, chat GTT or you can't use online
chat with your classmates during your exam period.
But it's an online exam and, uh, in this exam,
1 A4 double-sided notes is avail uh is accessible,
so you can prepare your notes and bring that one to your online exam.
So that is the final exam. And then If you go
through the home, And
You can see there are recent announcements.
I've already put the where to find the recording in my first
announcement, and I've also put this one,
last Friday, so that you know where we are right now,
right? So you can go through this collaborate and then to our session.
Um, and then, So
Here, there are two links. One link, OK,
if you just uh copy that link to your browser,
you should be able to find the weekly updated events from school
of ICT. That's just general information.
And sometimes we will hold some meetings and cyber events,
uh, sometime event, yeah, yeah, I think there will be one.
Um, in South Bank soon, uh, which, through which we
invited some industry partner and they will discuss the,
um, cybersecurity, uh, situation currently,
uh, in the, uh, in that event. So there will be one,
but we will keep updating the information here so you can use this link to check out the
updated events. And then there's another suggestion box,
but this is for school of ICT general suggestion box,
not necessarily to be specific to a course,
right, but for this course, specifically,
and you want to approach and discuss, and you can always approach me,
OK, or another course, um, teaching member.
And this is a trimester overview, so how we organize the course week by week.
And there will be a link clickable um later when
we release all the stuff. So now probably you can only click all this,
um, but not be able to click all the following links because the material were not
opened yet, not released yet. OK. Um,
so if you go to the module, and you can also find in this announcement here,
so where to find the very first one, OK,
where to find the recording. I've put a screenshot here,
so which, uh, you should click, collaborate,
and then, and this button, and then recording,
and then find the right session. OK. Because uh so this is where
you can find a recording for this online session.
OK. Many students, they will use the, this place to do their review later
before final exam. So click collaborate,
click this one, and click recording. But we don't have any recording yet,
right, because the course just started after today,
and there will be a recording for this online session which will appear here.
And after the workshop session, you can also see a workshop session here.
And sometimes you need to um put the right filter and to filter out the
right session, but normally it will just be sorted in order or in time order.
OK? So this is where you should go to find
your recording. Uh, and by the way, attendance
is not mandatory for the course, but it will be good if you attend
lively and you can pop your questions in your chat.
And by the way, this chat. will be also,
I think automatically be recorded by collaborate.
So for everyone's notice, if you have really relevant
question regarding the course content, you can always ask your question here,
OK? Uh, just do not post too many messages which are irrelevant to the course,
right? So we do have some students, they discuss something else during,
uh, just to let you know, the chat messages are recorded.
I think when you access this recording and you can,
there's an option for you to open the chat,
um, because sometimes when we discuss some question,
and then there will be some discussion, I might just go to the question and the chat,
and then I explain and so that this is the place.
OK, you can uh view the question there and then you can know what
I'm talking about, OK, when I address some questions.
So the chat, uh, I mean, um, Omar is
asking not mandatory. I mean, OK, when, because
some students they ask me, uh, they have work commitment or they're sick and then they
can't attend a session lively, will they be penalized?
I said no, you won't be penalized, OK, we are not,
we will not assess you based on your attendance,
but you should attend your session. Uh, on time,
uh, week by week. If you have work commitment on the day,
it's OK, you missed that online session lively,
and you should always come back to the recording later to catch
up with what, what we have learned on, uh,
on that day, OK? So that's what I mean. And for the workshop,
um, So if you're enrolled in person, um,
with an in-person workshop at campus, you should always come to the
campus. Although our workshop tutor, I've told them,
OK, you won't you shouldn't penalize a student if he really can't attend
due to some um special occasion. Um, but
we would encourage you to come to your, to your On campus
workshop, because when you reserve a space,
that reserve, that, that space is reserved for you,
right? And other students, they can't enroll because you have occupied that place.
And then if you don't always come to that session or that time doesn't suit you,
you can talk to us and we will try to do some swapping for you.
So that you can be there in person because you will have benefits you can
discuss with your classmates, you can discuss with your tutor,
right? You can always um probably get more out of your two hour
session rather than just the learning through online recording by yourself,
right? So, um, so that's how we
work in those, uh, schedule. So I hope you can attend in person if
you have registered an in-person session.
And if you register online, and you always come to online session,
and I will, um, not me, probably for this course,
yeah, another campus convenor will be online lively to answer all the questions
during your workshop session, OK? Um,
Yeah, so if you can't attend in person one,
but you have reserved a spot, and please write us an email,
and we know there will be a vacant, OK, place and we can offer to another
student. OK? Um, you can switch to online,
mm. That's, that's totally fine. OK. So the assessment will
be based on your workshop quiz, OK. Uh, not this
self-review quiz. The self-review quiz is just 10 multiple choice questions.
You can use them to test your own knowledge,
um, but there will be some I'll just show you
one we have had in this workshop, just quickly
show you. So this will be, for example, not released yet.
But you can see that one and that's uh 5 questions.
Um, normally sometimes it's 5 or 5 to 10 questions,
and then you can answer and you don't have to submit,
OK. Um, I think I, I probably will
set, set, set up that one a bit differently this year.
So you can open your quiz. And then you just need
to submit, not, not have to, you don't have to submit during the session,
OK, your workshop session, you can always try practice your workshop,
um. And then you submit uh by the
next Wednesday. So for example, if we have one assessment item for this
week 3, right, and you get everything released on week 3 or probably
in week 2 already, and you can go through everything like lecture
and learning activity, and a workshop. And then After
you do the practice, you can then go to your test,
right, you can then go to your test and then you submit that one.
By the following Wednesday, which means the week 4th Wednesday.
So the workshop quiz works like that. You don't have to submit during the workshop
session. OK. It will be, um, the due
by Wednesday, the next Wednesday, OK, 5 o'clock.
So, that's, that's about the workshop. Nathan is asking,
are all workshops in person, not online.
So if you're enrolled in person, you should go to your in-person session.
If you enrolled online, you can do every workshop online and
submit your quiz by the following Wednesday.
So if it's a week 3 and you submit by week 4 Wednesday,
OK, and then, yeah, so that's how this um submission
deadline works. Um, and then about
the module, I'd like to show you the modules will
always be like the lecture slides. OK. You can always
find the lecture slides in lecture place.
And there will be um Simple introduction about what will
be included in that lecture, and there will be some pre-lecture recording,
OK. So this recording I've put an announcement,
right, you should watch your pre-lecture recording,
that's why it's called a pre-lecture recording.
You should watch your pre-lecture recording before your lecture.
Because that will give you better understanding for your lecture content,
OK? So in this week, there have been 2.
Um, 9 minute video which talks about the basics in
cybersecurity, and then you should watch them,
and then you come to today's lecture, and then you go to the workshop
to complete your workshop activity. And then you open your
quiz to answer the quiz. Submit that one by the following Wednesday.
So that's how this course should work, OK?
So this pre-lecture recording has the slides I
attached here, OK, I will attach for each week.
And then there will be the lecture slides I will use in our lecture,
um, time, OK, it will also be released a week ahead,
right? And then In the next place, which will normally
be learning activity. So the learning activity
will be some supplementary material, uh,
you can use to better understand the content because I know many of you
probably are not from computer science or IT background,
but you want to know a bit better in the area.
So that's why I put something extra. In this learning
activity part, just for fun and not,
I mean, the content wise, it won't be assessed.
For example, this one just talked about some hacking my computer um
is the biggest threat in our world. I think it is talking about that.
And then this one is demonstrating how Tesla,
um, the operating system can be hacked. OK.
People are controlling that one to dance,
OK, uh, according, I mean, as the music goes,
and then the, the car is dancing because someone is hacking into the system,
right? And then this one is talking about two different types of uh
certification for cybersecurity area and the comparison.
So all of them, all of this video, I include them in because I have
viewed a bunch of videos and I thought some of them are relevant and very interesting,
so I include it in, in this learning activity part.
And each week, there will be some, there will be some links and maybe some
video. Um, but they will not be assessed,
OK, in the final exam. Just some interesting video,
uh, especially for the students benefit if you're not
from IT background. OK. And this one introduce
Linux and Unix because we will use Linux operating system.
Um, to, uh, actually practice those activity,
workshop activity. So I want you to understand how was
the history of that Linux operating system,
and then you understand a bit better about the system itself.
OK? So, the next would be uh
workshop. So for the future week, it will always be organized this way,
um, lecture slides, and then the learning activity,
which will be some supplementary material.
Uh, and then the workshop, OK, the actual workshop material will be
found here. So there will be, uh, workshop slides and workshop
instruction, tutorial document, um, two of them will be available here,
but for this week, we don't have a workshop yet.
OK, I provided some material, um, this is one YouTube video
which, um, if you just, uh, um, drag that down a bit and
you can find the actual professor Wen Liangdu.
is talking about the design of his material and we use some
of them, right, not every week, it's depending on,
dependent on that. But it gives you a lot of
good information and resource you can explore by yourself,
right? So you can just have words, right,
um, per view. And then there will be um some,
this is optional because I know some of you already knew
Linux operating system. Also, you, you, you know how to
install a VM, OK, virtual machine in your computer.
I know some students, they like computer science background and they want to explore on their
own computer. Uh, that's OK. So this is the instruction for you to
do. You can do that one, but you don't have to if you don't want to,
uh, use up your space in your computer because this requires quite,
uh, many space in your computer, like hard drive,
disk, and the memory. If your computer is moderate,
it's not very high performance one, and then you probably can't
afford two virtual machines running at the same time in your own computer.
This is why we actually provide a cloud service solution,
um, to every student enrolled in this course.
So you don't have to install it in your own computer,
you can just use your cloud account. OK,
we will provide that later. We'll create it this week.
And we will provide to our students later this week.
And you can just use your cloud account to simulate everything and to do the
practice in the cloud server, OK.
Um, how much space does it require, um, at
the moment, if you install this version 20,
I think it requires about 20 gigabytes hard drive disk,
and it requires some memory as well, um,
as it's running. Uh, I have one. Uh, quite old
Mac model. And for, for M1 and above, um,
Mac system computer, they don't allow virtualization.
So you probably can't install any virtual machine on your,
um, very new Mac computer. But I have one,
I think an iOS 5. I installed that one before,
right? That allows. However, when I try to
run two virtual machines at the same time in that computer,
that computer will be done, OK, will be stuck.
So, so if you want to try, you can try version
1616 works. OK, I think I put it somewhere here.
So alternately, this one also works for this course which requires less resource.
So you can try that one, and that's probably better.
Um, but I'd say, mm, to avoid all the, I mean,
difficult, technical difficulty, and you can always try cloud account.
So that does exactly the same thing. But you really wish to explore
more, um, activity offered by this professor Wang
Lianghu, who is the American, um, Professor and
then he built up, I think this is more than 10 year project they have
provided, they built up a lot of stuff in their website.
So I've I, I will give a brief introduction in week two.
And then you can see that one, we have a lot of stuff and
for the people in cybersecurity domain to learn
by themselves. So we, because we found that resource really
useful for, for new students. So that's why we We designed
several uh workshops based on their resource,
but then we use some of uh our own as well.
So, so, um, this is the introduction about their resource.
So if you're interested, you can have a look.
And if you want to, um, study this subject by your
own, And there's always free resource offered by
those uh Professor Wen Liangdu online as well.
OK, so, however, those are all technical stuff,
OK, very technique stuff. So I don't think if without supervision
you might, you, you can go through everything,
OK. So, but here is the introduction, OK,
you can have a look. If you have time, but we don't have workshop in week one,
but you can always use your workshop, workshop time to our to explore all
this stuff, OK. But our workshop will start from next week.
OK, so after this, um, there will be
Actual introduction about the course, uh,
I would say This part, I always would like
to keep that one as a beginning because um all
these materials and recording, uh we provide everything to students.
You can access recording, you can download the recording,
I, I actually changed the setting to be downloadable,
right? So, but please don't make them public in any way.
That's the Griffiths copyright um matter,
right? And also the tool and methods you learn from this course are not
to be used for any illegal purpose because you will learn how to sniff people,
how to, uh, crack the password, uh, using some free tool.
So I wish you just use them for learning purpose,
OK. Um, I will.
OK. So I'll just try to turn off that. OK,
I'll keep your chat here. In my other screen so that I know
when you have questions. OK, so, This is what
we will learn in this course.
We will learn who the bad guys are and what methods they will
use, right? And they will also learn how to protect cyberspace.
We will talk about 3 dimensions, OK? People,
technology, and policy. Um, I use a different color,
um, if you can see that blue, orange, and pink color,
OK, and then that means technology part,
people part, and policy part. And in this pie,
module 1234. And in our module 2 and 3,
that will be mostly based on technology part.
And then in module 4, we will touch policy and the people part.
OK? So these are the general contents we will include for each module.
And then here is an out out out outline.
Um, the blue color means technology part,
and you can see the main part of this course will be based on technology.
And then there will be 2 weeks, OK, on policy part,
and then 1 week on people's aspect. So only
when we have all three dimension. Protected or
or we learn the skill how to, I mean, using these three
dimensions and we can really protect our cyberspace.
Otherwise, the people always say, OK, technology is the main part,
but not necessarily to be the most important part.
Sometimes people are the most important part for protecting the cyberspace
actually. So it's just that the people need to know how to use this
technology and how to. Design the policy so
that make sure this technology reach a certain
standard, right? And how to make those policies so that people
were under constraint and technology were properly used,
right? So that's how we can protect the cyberspace.
So all these three dimensions are all equally important,
OK. But of course, we need to learn more about technology and then we know how to
Uh, ensure the certain standard, and then we know how to,
um, Uh, improve the cyber awareness for people,
right? So this is how we will learn the course,
OK, learn this essential part of cybersecurity in the first introduction
course in this cybersecurity, OK. And then,
so this is how you, each week, I would expect you
to do a pre-lecture recording, OK, before your lecture time.
Um, and then you attend one-hour lecture per week,
right? And then you should attend a two-hour workshop,
um. After your lecture, OK? And then you provide your
quiz, right, the answer, um, before the following Wednesday.
OK, so this is the assessment in total. Um,
please be aware there will be a hurdle in your final exam,
so you can get 40% in your,
uh, 8 quiz, OK, some good students, they just get full marks.
And then, in the final exam, Uh, if you only got
30%, um, you will be over 50 in
total, but you won't be able to pass the course because there's a hurdle.
So which means in your final exam, you should get more than 40%
to really get past the course. So it's still very important for your final exam,
um, to get, um, enough points, OK? Uh,
but 40 out of 100 should be an easy, OK,
easy, uh, score for you to get if you,
um, keep pace with every week study, OK?
I would say only students who do not attend the workshop,
who do not, um, provide their or submit their quiz on time,
and then they don't understand why this quiz question,
um, I mean, the answer should be this way,
or they don't understand why the activity was designed this way,
why, what's the theory behind those workshop practices.
Only people. Who don't try to understand the theory behind
and they probably won't be able to um pass the final exam.
Otherwise, yeah, if you go through every week,
OK, workshop activity um by yourself and you understand
why. Are those questions answered, be answered those ways,
right? And why the theory, what theory is supporting
your activity, and then you will be fine,
OK? And a lot of them will get distinction,
high distinction after the final. And this course is very practice based
and also. Um, application-based. We try to,
we try not just to let you to memorize those theory or those
concepts. We try to let you understand the series through practicing
and through Um, Through your
practicing and also the understanding applications,
and then you know how to use, utilize your knowledge,
OK, in reality. So that's how uh we're trying to do,
OK? And I'll show you some example of what you will learn in this course,
OK, later. So this is about the time, and then the teaching team,
um, and you can find updated teaching team in our course site anyway.
OK. About the textbook, there's no single book which
covers everything because from the three dimensions you can see,
we, we actually, we, we see this one, this part,
OK. On this
part, you can see we have 2 weeks in network security,
right? For network security protocol itself can be a course,
OK. It, some books, they just talk about this TCPIP network
protocol, and um just in one book, I have that book
actually here in my bookshelf. So if you don't have
any background knowledge for the network protocol,
you might want to um Read a little bit, right.
And then for cryptography, itself can be a course,
OK, and uh some, some books are really thick to cover all the cryptography
algorithms, but we will focus on the 22 most popular
uh algorithms and a lot of application built on top of those cryptography
algorithms. So, uh, we will discuss that one.
And then for the authentication, access control itself,
then again, it can be a book, right? So there's no single book
covering all this essential part of CyberSecu as a start point.
So which is why we don't use a single book as a,
as a uh ref a textbook. So, but I will provide
enough material for you to learn in our lecture slides and
also learning activity. And, uh, in
your self-review quiz. So those materials should be um utilized
for you to learn this course. And then you can also um see the
very first one, which is this one, this book,
CISSP all in one exam guide. I created
um my access control, authentication part and also
policy part um through this book, OK?
I created the cryptographer chart based on some
cryptography, um, reference book. Like this one
here, and then I actually excluded some
software security part from this course because they're more um relying on
coding and software design part. I know um as an
introductory course, maybe um that's too hard for students without
IT background. So, but, but we use
some very um little component for you to understand the
cryptography algorithm. OK. And I will just give you the
coding, the code, um, directly, so you don't have to write
code one by one, line, line by line. So that's OK.
Um, but some material was from this professor Wen Liangdu's,
um, seed lab. So he has, uh, I think more than 10 years project
which build up a lot of practice in the area,
OK, which are all very heavily technical content.
Um, OK, so these are the useful reference book,
um. You don't have to really buy one. I will
try to provide as much as possible in our court site.
OK, you have plenty of them to, to read and review,
right? To read and review. Um, there are also some useful
video, probably you find the, will be good for your understanding if
you really found some content you, uh, some relevant knowledge is
missing and you can always try to search them.
OK, from different resource. OK, so,
Firstly, I'd like to talk about why I study the cybersecurity
and why does the cybercrime exist and what are the key options in the area.
Um, but for this module, so this is week one module,
and then we have these two basics, OK? Um,
video productory coding already, um, published,
published online. So you should try to understand what is CIA model
and what are the differences between risks.
Threats, vulnerabilities, exploits. So those are different concepts.
They will appear um throughout the course.
And if you don't understand this difference,
you might sometimes get confused with some concepts.
OK, so try to understand all this difference.
OK. And then, and then today we will talk about why I study
cybersecurity, to give you some motivation,
and I think all these questions pop up in your mind when we talk about cybersecurity,
right? So now let's look at the firstly,
abs and software, and here is one
site. I won't open each site because I'm running out of time.
Um, so when you go there, um, you can see the updated
2026 material already, um, because now it's March,
and it will It will actually keep increasing each
year until 25 and in March there's a decreasing because it,
it only counted up to three months now, right?
So, so it has all these different types of vulnerability.
Vulnerability means the weakness, and each weak vulnerability has an
ID given ID. Some of them are existing
vulnerability, some of them are unknown vulnerability.
So when people learned what the vulnerability was caused by,
they will analyze that existing vulnerability.
They will give an ID to that vulnerability.
So this is in each year, how many different types of vulnerability were
identified, OK, during that year. And you can see that is keep
increasing each year. And if you go there,
you can see the updated data. And then you can see
what's the cause of that vulnerability. Some of them are overflow,
um, buffer overflow, and some of them are SQL injection,
and some of them are XSS, some of them are CSRF.
As we go through the course, like next week,
we will talk about what is SQL, what is XSS,
what is CSRF, OK, all these different types of vulnerability we will discuss
next week. So as we, as we go through, you will understand a bit more
about all these causes of this um vulnerabilities.
And then And this website, if we go there,
quickly go there. Um, and then you would find
Sorry, it
to change it to Uh,
it doesn't, uh, it's not clear. I can't see which one is the.
No. Not
this one.
Just go to this website, it will show you.
I'll show you the new.
Brits OK. Lively captured by
this website. So I'm doing that one here,
and then you can see, it is updating actually,
that, that one was the last update by this website.
So it is capturing all the biggest data breaches and hacks,
and you can see a Throughout the years, and there
are different country and different big companies which has
reported breaches. And then you probably can see all of them are
different company. Some of them are in um this
like hotel, commercial company, and some of them are social
media company, Facebook and Twitter. And some of them might be the
government, place like Indian Citizen or some of
the other phone company and police. Uh, government,
so you can see that one, and if you go through the filter,
and you can see how many of them are financed.
The, just, that's just one future. And I remember I saw some of them are
like the JP Morgan, um, some in some years,
um, the, how big the dot is means how
severe of that breach is, OK? And probably
money-wise, so how many, that's 160 million and that's 76
million. And so on. So, so this is a recorded one,
you can of course see a different uh sector.
So it will just show you all this information.
The government sector, you probably can see a lot of different um place
as well. So, this will show you the world's biggest
breaches, which has happened during the last probably 5 to 10 years,
right? Yearly by, year by year. And then,
if you If you look at the equipment and car,
uh, which we normally probably don't think much about.
However, um, this one is a big uranium, I
think the manufacturer company and then they have been hacked.
I think 10 years, more than 10 years ago.
And then, of course, nothing happened. Uh,
however, this big, um, I think the the
manufacturing company can be controlled by the bad people
using this one to create those nuclear. Um,
stuff, right, and then it can cause, Um,
serious damage to the whole world, right?
And then, the other equipment you can see,
uh, this is a car, uh, actually two people,
they are ethical hackers, they're quite famous in the domain.
And then they, they use their technique to hack into,
um, cars operating system, and then they
actually control your steering wheel and your,
um, brakes and so on. And then your car when you drive on the highway will
be out of your control, and then the bad people can hack into your system and can,
can control your car. So, these two people,
they just demonstrated that one. And then,
um, and then this one, I include that video in our learning
activity. You can see that one in one conference.
To, um, Tesla car were dancing
with the music, um, because people try to hack into their system and
just to control the, the car. Right? And then you can always
see another type of equipment. This is a pacemaker,
which meant to be embedded in people's hearts.
And then, however, because it was secured a hole.
And half a million people were affected and then
they have to take out, they have to take out the pacemaker
and to patch the security hole and then get them back into the people's
heart again. So, so you can see if there's a security issue.
Um, it will actually affect every aspect in our life,
right? And every different type of, uh, equipment,
computer, um, this kind of equipment or even pacemaker,
or the big, um, electricity, um, manufacturer or water
facilities, all this kind of stuff, controlling system or even,
uh, railway control system, they can all be hacked,
right? And now here is the cyber breaches,
data breaches. I just give you um this as an example.
This is old top 10 data breaches. And you can see
um Through what? OK.
That has been breached. And when was, is it,
when was it breached? And then what type of company?
You can see that big Microsoft company and some
uh famous like Uber and Red Cross, non-profit um
association, right? And what kind of data were breached?
Most of them are personal data. Of course,
some of them may be uh the source code, OK,
were breached, right? And how many were
leaked, right, the, the amount. So,
really it happens in every domain, everywhere,
right? And if we, if you, that's why the,
there has been different news. About what kind of
shortage. Are there in this domain, and then,
So according to different source, you can always say they had a huge
gap in this area and a lot of company now,
they're actually hiring, hiring people to fix their system
issue or to do more um secured
software development, right? So, there has been a lot of
position calling for uh security architect,
security engineer. And so on, right? So,
So what will you learn in this course then?
OK, we have talked about 3 dimensions, um,
people, technology, and the policy, and technology doesn't solve everything,
right? And that's why the people are learning.
Through Through all these three dimensions to fix the issue.
So what we will learn is in this course we will talk about ransomware.
So this is just some examples of what you will learn in this course.
So how to prevent ransomware hacks, OK, attacks,
right? And then about the bank coder, and you probably can see there's
RSA, which is the fundamental algorithm which
can support our secure banking system. And we will learn
what RSA is, OK. What is that essential algorithm?
What's, what is its function, and, how it works,
OK, in reality. So we'll learn that one and,
in cryptography part. And we'll also try simulating
um bad guy. OK, like this,
and um maybe some good guy um in the, in
the, in, in your website, and then uh in your virtual machine,
and how the bad guy is sniffing the packets between two users,
right? So try to simulate those environments in virtual machine and you
understand how the people can sniff the packets and And learn,
and then do some analysis, right? So with a different network protocol,
um, how those protocols are protecting this
network traffic, OK, online, going online,
right? So you will see all those stuff in this course.
And then, um, we'll also learn some policy stuff.
This is the most popular, um, Australian government
supported, uh, essential aid. So we'll learn what that is.
And then if you work in a company now, um,
relevant to the, the cybersecurity, you probably have already
been asked to embed essential aid in
all, in your company, OK? So that essential aid is provided by Australian government.
And then, which is um the policy-wide policy side of things.
OK then, why does cybercrime exist?
So this explains how uh why that exists
always. When there's a motivation. When there's opportunity,
when they have the ability. And then they can,
there always be something happen, right?
So that's what, why this MAO framework
model um explains why cyber, cybercrime is um
like destiny of this world, right? So there will always be some
behavior, cybercrime behavior existing, existing in this world.
And about the ability, you probably can see,
um, ability doesn't necessarily to be We have design ability.
They can actually purchase those free hacking tools in the
market, in the dream market. So, uh, we call that black
market, but we call that dream market. And then they can spend some
little money to buy, OK, that just depends on the old the
transfer, I think the transferring rate,
right, Bitcoin. Um, but yeah. They have a price
online, and then they can purchase those tools,
and they just purchase and then, and then launch those tools and then they try to
hack people, right, so this is just one ransomware.
OK, and so, They have this ability, they can just use money to buy and
then they have some motivation and they also found an opportunity because another person
is too vulnerable. He just click anything and then click any link in
the email, so there's opportunity there,
and then here is the people with ability with this ransomware.
And also, um, there's a motivation because he probably wants to make
money through this way, right? So when we have all these three factors,
there must be something happen, happening,
right? So, why they always win because this is asymmetric,
defending and attacking because To
defend, we have to close every window for the bad people
to break in. But for the bad people, they just need to find one small
hole to break into the system. So this is already a
symmetric, which is why we say, OK, it's so hard to prevent everything
not to be happening, right? You have to take care of the system itself,
you have to take care of the people, make sure they have higher cyber awareness,
and they have to find, close every window to prevent
those bad people to break in. So this is asymmetric.
And also there are existing secure insecure system
and people remain vulnerable. So these are all the reasons why cybercrime
exists. So to protect our data network system,
and then we will have to understand who they are,
their motivation, and how do they get in.
And this is a very um Similar to like The Art of
War by Sun several 1000 years ago, and then they found if you have
to win the battle, you have to know who they are,
you have to know their motivation and how do they get in,
right? So that's why we will learn who the bad guys are and,
and there are 3 types of hacker, we normally call them black hat,
white hat, and gray hat, right? So just some
um. Some, uh, definitions here, not necessarily to
be remembered. OK, and then how to become a cybersecurity
professional, uh, we want the cybersecurity profession to have very broad knowledge,
of course, because this is a multidisciplinary area.
And sometimes you got to know a lot of stuff to be really good in the
area. However, that doesn't mean you can't,
um, start if you're not IT background. There'll always be something for
you in a different stage, because If you go to this website,
you can see there is some pathway. You can start with
something, uh, at the beginning, which is a feeder role and
entry-level cybersecurity role, if you have had a little bit of information
in the area, you can come to the entry level and then to the mid-level and
to the advanced level. And this is a, what is the average
salary um provided by this link. Uh you can always try,
um, get some information by chat, GPT or by yourself,
right? And you would know how, what is the payment scale.
And also, this website, the good thing is it also tells you the
top skill requested. And the top certification requested,
so that you know what type of certification might be highly recognized by different role or
different company, right? And what are the top skills required in
the domain. So, um, it gives you all that information here.
And then, so the certification is always,
um, like good thing for you to go through,
but to learn this introductory course definitely would benefit to,
towards your certification in the future.
Um, uh, normally, uh, proper certification means you to get
enough knowledge and also get enough practice,
um, experience in this domain, OK, in this
domain. So these are just, uh, some. Different
organizations offered different certification and there are different uh
level of recognition in the market, also depends on which company,
right? But of course, many of them are equivalent.
You can always claim, OK, you have CISSP which can be equivalent to
something like uh CASP. I provided one video which
compare, compares these two, right? Like cer certified asset
hacker. Uh, which is provided by ethical,
um, yeah, EC Council, I think they're calling that ESCO something,
right? So this is the biggest one ISC, um,
I think from America. So, and the CISCO itself also has its
own certification in security. So I think these are the
fairly easy one. Um, but if you in
Cisco and you can consider to do something,
like I saw some material, I, I, I did prepare some material based on their
CCMP security, um, material, OK.
So different. One, and to get an understanding on how
technical or less technical or advanced or beginner
level, and it has this roadmap. So I prepared this one for you to
get some good understanding about maybe um depending on your role and
your background, you can start with something,
right, easier and then you go to more uh technical um pathway and
that's something you can consider or refer to,
OK, this map. And then, so this is just about
some uh more information about certification.
So these are the popular one. and then this video is the one
I included in the chat. OK. So some career advice,
quite obvious, you can read by yourself.
And so this is uh all about today. Um, by the way,
before I leave, I just want to keep this one in recording,
uh, because I already
Activate our Team's channel. So if you log into your
Teams, you enroll this course before this morning.
That you should have uh access to this team's channel.
And in this one, you can always, OK. Chat
with someone, OK, chat with your classmate or chat with me,
uh, just to quickly type a message and you can use a tag,
OK, with at and tag a particular person.
You can tag me, OK, if you have a question to me,
and you can just put my email message which is
hui.tian@griffiths.edu.au,
and I can tag all. Uh, let me just
tag you quickly, all staff, all students in this
course, um.
I just try to write one message here. So I post this message so that you can
find, find our team site. OK. So
then, so this is our team's chat, you can always post your chat
message after the session. Of course during the lecture session you can always,
you can always um Use a chat box to pop your question,
but after the course you can use this channel to discuss your questions here.
OK. So that's all for today. Um, sorry to be a